so another example here and this one I
wanted to put in because it's an
important match for me personally I had
a bad record against the Rodney Rodney
Morris here rape Mosconi co-player Hall
of Famer great player of course good
enough to talk about that great champion
a lot of heart but his Mosconi record
was unbelievable for years and he
drilled me on a few occasions I didn't
get picked for the 2010 team um and I
was a little bit sick about that
personally but 2011 I was right there
again and I have to play Rodney in the
third match of day one and I was really
nervous because I had gone to a pretty
rough period the birth of my daughter
was extremely long which left me a
little bit in shock for a while and nice
little shot there guys what that meant
was that my game went down for a little
bit and I had to go through this this
was a great learning experience for me
personally and I was still very nervous
carrying that over into this tournament
the Mosconi Cup and then again I did a
lot of work I was visualizing really
strongly before the event and I got
extremely rewarded in this match that
shot on the one was a good example and
all the little details I can remember
from this I was just I saw everything so
clear it was really a moment of being in
the zone we talked about that in the
course of course in the course of course
and we need a clear mind we need a
relaxed body we have to be prepared our
game has to be sharp and then you get
these moments in sports that they call
the zone right where everything is just
blocked out you're executing very easily
everything feels automatic and I can
remember clearly that this rack
for me in the Mosconi cup was a moment
of being in the zone I didn't see
anybody I didn't hear anybody things
were clicking for me little carom shots
like this one I still had to judge it
because the cloth is really fast I have
to judge how fast the Fife was going
towards that corner and it was a great
moment I was able to beat Rodney
6-nothing but which he's beaten me many
times so it's not about showing that I
could beat him 6 nothing but it's just
about this one rack and it was a pretty
special rack for me personally so I
wanted to put it in here as an example
of how things were really clicking and
if you can get in the zone in the
Mosconi cup it's a special moment in
your life because it doesn't happen all
that often because the pressure is so
intense so if you have one of these
moments it's it's huge and I'm five
balls away and I remember clearly even
the course we talked about a
visualization exercise that's that has
to do with the bottles and basically you
visualize six or seven bottles standing
in front of you or shot glasses or
whatever you want to call it and you
label them with mental things that you
would like for instance concentration
relaxation power these kind of things
and you take these shot glasses one by
one and you focus on the feeling that it
gives you and I've worked on that for
two weeks and before I went into the
arena I did this real quick you can the
the more you do it the faster it goes
and I remember standing on the top of
the stairs I did that shot glass
exercise within 20 seconds
and I could just feel the power of it
and it was it's just a great example of
what it can bring you so focused sorry I
ran through that wreck pretty smoothly
Rodney great player a lot of respect for
him and I put a point on the board for
the team they're so good example they're
guys for visualization
[Music]